<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rich Somerfield</title>
    <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rich Somerfield</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.richsomerfield.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.richsomerfield.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi.
I live and work near Manchester, UK.
For work, I&amp;rsquo;m a Principal Software Engineer at Ivanti (nee LANDESK, nee AppSense) mostly working on shipping v1 products - the three most recent projects have involved; cloud technologies (AWS, Azure), web-UI, web-services, and Windows/Mac agents. I love the dynamic and creative nature when collaborating with a team to birth new v1 products.
Previously at AppSense I was Head of Research; leading a small, skilled team to identify and solve complex problems, and explore next generation markets and technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spends (iOS) - Pocket Money Made Simple</title>
      <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/apps/spends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.richsomerfield.com/apps/spends/</guid>
      <description>Download

Simple  Set a daily amount for each child. Swipe left or right on a child to quickly reward good behaviour, or punish bad behaviour. Tap into each child to add or remove any monetry amount.  Screenshots 
See your children  Quickly reward good behaviour  Change childs details (including avatar) and see the transaction history
  Add or remove any amount - when they receive money gifts, or, they spend it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TextBar - Mac App</title>
      <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/apps/textbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.richsomerfield.com/apps/textbar/</guid>
      <description>TextBar is a tiny but powerful app that lets you add any text to your MenuBar.
 TextBar v2  TextBar Live  Monitor TextBar output from multiple machines on the web.  Dynamic script control WebView menu items More details here: New for v2  Overview:  Download app || Purchase 
 “TextBar is an awesome app which solves a problem that I have been struggling with for at least three years” - MacStories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating a website</title>
      <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/blog/new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.richsomerfield.com/blog/new-site/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Last time I switch the design of my blog, I switched to Hugo. After a bit of theme customization I had a pretty good working system. However, it didn&amp;rsquo;t take long until I tweaked one of the static generated output files.
This tweaking continued for the next few years&amp;hellip; until now.
I&amp;rsquo;ve stuck with Hugo, but have chosen a different theme and made my customizations - mostly to make it work like a fully functioning website (with a blog), and not just a &amp;lsquo;single page site&amp;rsquo;, or a &amp;lsquo;blog with an simple about page&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>