<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rich Somerfield</title>
    <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rich Somerfield</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.richsomerfield.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TextBar - Mac App</title>
      <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/apps/textbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.richsomerfield.com/apps/textbar/</guid>
      <description>TextBar is a tiny but powerful app that lets you add any text to your MenuBar.
 
Major new version available - v3. No upgrade fee. 
 Want to monitor TextBar from multiple machines on the web - see TextBar Live. 
Overview:  Download app || Purchase 
 “TextBar is an awesome app which solves a problem that I have been struggling with for at least three years” - MacStories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airport Picnic</title>
      <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/blog/2017-05-21-airport-picnic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.richsomerfield.com/blog/2017-05-21-airport-picnic/</guid>
      <description>Took the kids out to Manchester Airport Visitors Park. I expected them to get bored quickly, but, instead, they were still enjoying it 3 hours later.
My friend came over too. We had fun and got some nice photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos</title>
      <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/blog/2017-05-18-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.richsomerfield.com/blog/2017-05-18-photos/</guid>
      <description>I been a keen photographer for many years. It started with a film camera, developoing black &amp;amp; white photos in the darkroom. The feeling when you develop your contact prints and then see the full-sized photo emerge from the chemicals; I love that process.
For over 3 years I took a photo every day and posted it to Blipfoto. They was a massive help in seeing photos, as the pressure of it being daily forces you to look everywhere for a photo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.richsomerfield.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi.
I live and work near Manchester, UK.
For work, I&amp;rsquo;m a Principal Software Engineer at Ivanti (nee LANDESK, nee AppSense) mostly working on shipping v1 products - the three most recent projects have involved; cloud technologies (AWS, Azure), web-UI, web-services, and Windows/Mac agents. I love the dynamic and creative nature when collaborating with a team to birth new v1 products.
Previously at AppSense I was Head of Research; leading a small, skilled team to identify and solve complex problems, and explore next generation markets and technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spends (iOS) - Pocket Money Made Simple</title>
      <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/apps/spends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.richsomerfield.com/apps/spends/</guid>
      <description>Download

Simple  Set a daily amount for each child. Swipe left or right on a child to quickly reward good behaviour, or punish bad behaviour. Tap into each child to add or remove any monetry amount.  Screenshots     
  Download</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating a website</title>
      <link>http://www.richsomerfield.com/blog/2017-05-10-new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.richsomerfield.com/blog/2017-05-10-new-site/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Last time I switch the design of my blog, I switched to Hugo. After a bit of theme customization I had a pretty good working system. However, it didn&amp;rsquo;t take long until I tweaked one of the static generated output files.
This tweaking continued for the next few years&amp;hellip; until now.
I&amp;rsquo;ve stuck with Hugo, but have chosen a different theme and made my customizations - mostly to make it work like a fully functioning website (with a blog), and not just a &amp;lsquo;single page site&amp;rsquo;, or a &amp;lsquo;blog with an simple about page&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>