<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Uncategorized | RichSomerfield.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://richsomerfield.com/blog/categories/uncategorized/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://richsomerfield.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-08T10:02:00-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://richsomerfield.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rich Somerfield]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Viewpoints]]></title>
    <link href="http://richsomerfield.com/blog/2009/04/30/viewpoints/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://richsomerfield.com/blog/2009/04/30/viewpoints</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I&rsquo;ve been spending quite a bit of time thinking about <em>viewpoints</em>.  It is something I&rsquo;ve never really paid much attention to, thinking that it was just one of those things.</p>

<p>The more I think about it, the more it travels up my ToDoList to <em>think about it more</em>.</p>

<p>Why am I blogging about this?  Well, during my day job, I have many conversations with many different people &ndash; often these are within meetings, but this also includes water-cooler chats, email, and many more forms of communcation. During these conversations, I&rsquo;m increasingly finding that it is important not only to understand my viewpoint (and here I mean view position, rather than point-of-view), but also the viewpoint of the person I&rsquo;m communicating with.</p>

<p>It is fair to say I&rsquo;m a bit of a scatter-brain.  I have lots of ideas all whizzing about, competing for attention, and generally distracting me from what I&rsquo;m actually meant to be doing.  I&rsquo;ve found the best way to separate these two activities is to ensure I allocate enough time for them, and put myself in to the environment that suits the activity best.</p>

<p>In very general terms, I love getting started on something new, but  struggle to take that thing to completion &ndash; I usually get to 80% completion, and start to get bored.  I suppose that suggests that I&rsquo;m better at the high-level concepts, than the low-level details.  Some people are much better at focusing on the low-level details and ensuring that are completely finished &ndash; but don&rsquo;t like dealing with the fuzzy high-level things.</p>

<p>I know this is a huge generalization, but I think time spent understanding your own and your collegues viewpoints, can go a long way to helping you move ideas and solutions forwards.  Otherwise, in my opinion, things get stuck in a cycle of repetition.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload]]></title>
    <link href="http://richsomerfield.com/blog/2009/04/08/information-overload/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://richsomerfield.com/blog/2009/04/08/information-overload</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been using RSS for a number of years.  As soon as I saw the concept, I was hooked.  Even to the point of developing my own RSS Reader (in C#), which I used for a while.  Given that I&rsquo;ve been using it for a number of years, I&rsquo;ve amassed a large collection of subscriptions, and am now struggling to keep on top of it all.</p>

<p>Everything I&rsquo;ve added to my collection will have been because I found something useful on that site at the point I added it.   But looking over them now it is hard to determine if I&rsquo;m still interested in it &ndash; and if I&rsquo;m not, will I be interested in a future post.  The problem therefore is, do I:</p>

<ul>
<li>Remove feeds to reduce the amount of content,</li>
<li>Only read posts from the last x days,</li>
<li>Keep everything, and try and read all of the titles.</li>
</ul>


<p>Why am I blogging about this, well with so much information, I can forsee a time where every company has their own department entirely purposed with agregating information (whether it be from the internet, books, radio, speeches, etc&hellip;).  This happens to some degree today, on an adhoc basis.  With more and more content being produced each day, this is going to require a more formal process.</p>

<p>PS: One huge problem I find with blogs, is that there are a large number of posts that are merely links to / copies of other posts.   Maybe a good starting point would be for an application to remove this duplication.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Computer History]]></title>
    <link href="http://richsomerfield.com/blog/2009/04/06/my-computer-history/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://richsomerfield.com/blog/2009/04/06/my-computer-history</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve always been interested in computers.  It started as a child when my dad bought a Amstrad CPC 464 computer &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amstrad_CPC">Wikipedia</a>.  Apart from the obvious &ldquo;HelloWorld&#8221; coding, my first really useful bit of development was when my dad bought a disk-drive for the Amstrad (the 464 was tape driven).  He&rsquo;d already bought a word-processor &ndash; from Dixons if I remember correctly &ndash; which was on a tape.  When we got the disk-drive, I managed to hack into the word-processor code (using the equivalent of Ctrl-Break, which as the source was loaded into memory, gave you direct access to it), using this I re-worked it so that it would use the disk-drive.  Not spectacular, but I was impressed with myself, and was intregued by what computers could do for me.</p>

<p>I remember going to my local library and looking for books on programming &ndash; there never seemed to be any.  Compare that to today when they is so much information it is a challenge just working out what is useful and what is not.</p>

<p>After the Amstrad my dad got a PC.  An ICL  286, with 100MB hard drive &ndash; which had to be partitioned into 32MB blocks.</p>

<p>Eventually, I ended up at University of Manchester, studing Computer Science.  I had a great three years and left with a top degree.  Following this I spent 9 months working for a company supplying solutions to the MoD, I learnt a bit, but was really frustrated that I couldn&rsquo;t just do things &ndash; so I left.</p>

<p>I then moved into the Telecoms sector, developing technology to process, consolidate and manage call records.  I really enjoyed this job, but unfortunately my office was closed as part of the telecoms crash of the early 2000&rsquo;s.  Within a few weeks of my redundancy I&rsquo;d managed to get a job at a security firm (SurfControl), which was developing solutions for the Windows platform.  This was the first time I&rsquo;d developed anything for Windows, and it was to be a steep learning curve.  My first piece of code for this company was fairly rubbish, but I learned a lot from this experience.  Given the sector we were in, and the solutions we were developing, we were all exposed to some pretty interesting and complex stuff.  After 5 years at this company, and learning a great deal, I was again made redundant (due to the company being bought by our nearest competitor).</p>

<p>My next employer is also my current employer.  For the first year I worked on a client side virtualization technology &ndash; exposing me to the compexities of working inside other peoples software.  I&rsquo;ve since changed roles, and am now the Software Research Team Lead.</p>

<p>At home, I use an iMac &ndash; which feels completely different to Windows, I&rsquo;ll write a post in the future with my feelings about the two different platforms.</p>

<p>I hope this gives you a bit of background about me.  If you want any more info, let me know and I&rsquo;ll follow up with a more detailed piece.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
